Hey Fox, today's video
is a comparison of health insurance plans, but
before starting this video, I
want to ask you a question: what is the definition of
a best health insurance
policy according to you? Do you
call that health insurance policy the best health insurance policy whose
features are very attractive, unique
features, revolutionary features,
or do you call that health insurance policy the
best whose claim settlement
ratio is excellent and whose approach is
customer-friendly? Fox, today's date,
insurance companies are competing to launch the best health
insurance policies.
Nowadays, a new competition has
started to launch unique and revolutionary health
insurance plans, but
no insurance company is
ready to compare the best claim settlement.
No insurance company
is ready to compare who will have the best
claim services and the best customer-friendly
approach. Fox, all the insurance
companies are only engaged in making money.
You should purchase a health insurance policy today,
declare all your diseases in it, declare
all your habits.
Give it to me and
you should read the 7580 pages policy word completely, even
after that no insurance company
can guarantee you that your claim will
not be rejected in the future. Now the
question arises that which
health insurance policy of which company should we purchase,
so there is only one best way for this
which I say in all my videos
that first of all you should
check the brand image of the insurance company because when a company
with a good brand image, that is, whose
brand image is very good in the market,
it will never reject your claim unnecessarily
and along with that you should
also
check other fundamentals of that insurance company, do not purchase any insurance policy only on the basis of claim settlement ratio or
in-currence cream ratio.
Fox,
in today's video I have brought
before you a comparison of three health insurance plans
and all these three health
insurance companies claim that
their health insurance plan is the best health
insurance plan in the industry and the
features they have are unique features, so stay tuned
to my video
till the end and you  If you have
not yet subscribed to the insurance service, then
subscribe to it now and
also press the bell icon and if you want to
purchase your insurance through the insurance service, then
you can also call us on the number given on the screen.
So Fox, then let us start the
comparison of three health insurance plans
and all these three health insurance plans, that is, all
three health insurance
companies are not new in the market. Well, Rino is
known to all.
I have brought the Elevate plan of IC Cello Bad, for
which I have already
made many videos before. Along with Niva
Bap Rish 2.0, this plan was launched in 2023.
Star Health has launched a new plan
recently, Superstar
Plan. I will compare this plan
with Niva Bap Rish 2.0 and
with the Elevate plan of ICC Lond because this
plan has all the features which are
not available in these two plans, that is, what
Star Health has done is that all the
features, that is, some features, they have
taken from Niva Bap Rish 2.0.
They have taken some features from Elevate plan of IC Lombard and also
taken some features from Aspire plan of Niva B and by
combining them they have prepared a plan called
Superstar. So let's start as usual with the
fundamentals of the insurance company.
If I talk about IIC Lombard then their
claim settlement ratio is 99 which is excellent. If we
talk about Niva Bupa then their
claim settlement ratio is 92. Star Health has a
claim settlement ratio of 87.
If we check the fundamentals then ICC Lombard will be the
best among them. Their solvency is also 2.5
against Niva Bupa which has 1.77 and Star
Health has 1.88. If we talk about network hospitals then
IC Lombard has 15000 network hospitals and
Niva Bupa has 10000. Their number has reduced
comparatively as compared to
earlier because
they have deeply analyzed some hospitals which have
14000.  Star Health has hospitals. We will
definitely talk about the claim process
because reimbursement is very important. The
claim process will be online.
You can process your claim by submitting it through the Eye Care app of ICICI Lombard. The same will be the case for
Niva Bupa.
You can process your claim through the app or through the link.
But
Star Health only has the offline option
available. You have to submit all the documents
in their branch, only then your
claim is settled. The average claim
ratio of ICICI Lombard is
78:54, Niva Bupa 65 and Star Health 65. So
these were the fundamentals of all the three insurance
companies. If I compare them, then ICICI
Lombard is the best in this. It is the oldest
company. It is fundamentally strong in general insurance
and
what are the financials of ICICI Lombard. If
everything comes inflating in the Elevate plan of ICICI Lombard, then the
insurance company will pay for it. You
can take unlimited claims and
when to take unlimited claims in Life?  You will
decide this Power Booster Power Booster is an
add-on feature in which 100% of your time will be
increased every year, there will be lifetime increase, there will be
increase for the whole life as long as you
run this policy, even if there is a
claim or not. There is also Jump
Start. You can take cover for five diseases
from 31 days - BP, Diabetes,
Hypertension, Hyperlipidemia, Asthma and
Obesity. If you have any one of these diseases,
you can take cover for them from 31 days.
After adding Jump Start, the
insurance will be for the same person, same illness,
but in the same person, same illness, you will have to give a
gap of 40 days. Maternity cover is
given as an add-on in this. Maternity will be covered after 24 months.
I am going to tell you about it in detail in the next slide.
With the add-on, you
can also take cover for durable equipment. So these were the
USPs of IC Lord's Elevate plan, i.e. its
features. You will talk about Niva Bupa's
Rish 2.2 plan.  They have Lock the Clock
as usual, which means it will be locked with the entry. The
premium will not increase until a claim is made, but the
premium will increase according to inflation.
This has been clarified by Niva Bhupa.
They have Booster Plus. They have four variants
in all four variants. You will get Booster Plus of
10x, 3x and 5x.
Your remaining time cover will keep accumulating. ReAssure Forever,
which means unlimited restoration will be available for meeting the same person.
You can avail it by meeting the same person the next day also.
Once ReAssure Restoration is
triggered, you will
not need to trigger it again. It will remain
triggered for whole life. The
minimum hospitalization
requirement will be of 10 hours.
Hospitalizations of more than 2 hours will be covered.
Now let's talk about Star Health's
Superstar Plan, in which they have combined all the
features from here and there
and launched a new plan.
They have said that
Freeze Your Age.  Up to 50 years, that is,
this feature is similar to lock the clock.
Your age will be locked with the entry.
Your premium will not increase until you take a claim,
but you will get this first facility only till 50 years,
after that you will not
get it. Unlimited cover same age as
your Infa Care is under ICC Lombard.
You can take unlimited claim once in your life,
but after the year in which you
take unlimited claim, your time limit for that year will become
zero. Superstar Bonus
same age, your Power Booster will
increase every year except your 100% time and will keep increasing for whole life.
Premium waiver for
one year. If any critical illness is diagnosed to the proposer
or if the proposer
dies in an accident, then one
year's premium renewal will be waived. So
these are the unique
features of all three, features of all three insurance plans,
health insurance plans. If
I talk about IC Lombard, then fundamentally it is a very
strong company.  The features are
also very good. Niva Bupa
Revolution feature was introduced in it a year ago
but Star Health has launched
a premium plan by adding the same features with Superstar.
Talking about the
basic features, first of all, the
time limit will come in all the three health insurance plans starting from Rs 5 lakh.
Unlimited
time limit will be available in IGC Lombard's Elevate plan
and Superstar but Niva Bupa
Rish 2.0 will have options up to Rs 1 crore only.
Entry age will be from 18 years to 65 years in
Niva Bupa Rish 2.0 and there will be no age limit in
your Star Superstar and
ICC Lombard's Elevate plan.
Policy tenure is 1 year, 2 years, 3 years in Niva Bupa Rish
2.0 and IGC Lombard's Elevate plan
but Star Health has
given premium options up to 5 years in Superstar.
You can avail discount by purchasing a 5-year policy.
Talking about variants, there
are four variants in IGC Lombard's Bronze Gold
Plus Platinum Plus and Titanium.  Plus, there will be
options for family size, two adult, three kits
in two plans, i.e.,
in IC Lombard and Star Superstar, and the
option of two adult four kits will be available in Niva Bupa Rish
2.0. If we talk about room rent, then
you can get a single private AC room
in IC Lombard's Elevate plan, but
you can downgrade and upgrade it
as an add-on, but in Niva Bupa Rish, there will be
no capping of any kind. If we talk about
other features in the same Star Superstar plan, then
next comes
ICU, ICCU. There is
no capping of any kind. There is no co-payment. No
mandatory co-payment will be levied on any plan.
Pre-hospitalization and post-
hospitalization will be
90 days pre and 180 days post in Elevate plan and Superstar, which is a
very good feature. They have increased the pre-
hospitalization
from 60 days to 90 days in both the policies,
but in Niva Bupa Rish 2.0, 60 and 180 days as
usual will remain. Modern treatment and day care
treatment will remain.  Both the policies have up to
Rs 1 lakh short cover but in Niva Bupa Rio 2.0 there will be a capping on robotic surgeries of Rs 1 lakh. If we
talk about e-consultation, it will be
unlimited. In ICC Lombard's
Elevate plan and in Niva Bupa's
Reassure 2.0 plan also, restoration will be
unlimited for the same person and same lineage.
As usual, I have already told you that if we
talk about ambulance road ambulance, then
you have Rs 1 lakh short cover. There is no capping.
If we talk about air ambulance, then there will be a
capping of hospitalization on Rs 1 lakh in your Superstar plan.
In Elevate, you will have to take it as an add-on, that is, if you
take the add-on, you will get the cover of air ambulance
but in Niva Bupa Ris 2.0
it will be an in-build cover. Talking about no claim bonus
in-build, here it will
go up to a maximum of 100% per annum. It will
not be reduced in case of a claim under the Elevate plan,
but there will be a booster plus of Rs 1 lakh in Reassure 2.0.
If you are taking Brij Plus, then
your Sum Shod Acumtica will be given till it reaches 3x, your Sum Shod Acumtica will be given
till it reaches 5x,
your Booster Plus means your Sum Shod Acumtica will be given
till it reaches 10x, your Sum Shod
Acumtica
cover will be for 36 months in all three policies
but in Superstar you
can reduce it, it will be for 36 months in Niva BPA Rish
2P but for two diseases you
can take cover from day one, Diabetes and
Hypertension, you will have to take a rider there,
Disease Management Rider. Talking about other features, if we
talk about annual health checkup, it will be an
add-on in Elevate,
you can take add-on cover there, that is, you
can get it covered by paying some additional premium,
but I do not recommend anyone
that you take its add-on,
save that much money and get
your annual health checkup done from the lab of your choice whenever you feel right,
but in Niva B it will be inbuilt for
₹5000000  The
maximum limit will be ₹0,000. There is
an add-on cover in Star Super Star as well, which is
alternative treatment which we
also call AYUSH treatment cover. There
is up to three time short cover in all three policies.
Talking about maternity,
this is an add-on cover in two plans like Elevate Plan and
Superstar Plan but
this facility is not available in Up Per Rish 2.0. You will get consumer benefits as an
add-on in all three plans.
Wellness program is available in IGC
Lord and Niva in Up Retu Points as well as in
Superstar. You
can avail it as well. You can earn 1000 points to
keep yourself healthy and fit
and you can get a discount of up to 20%.
Talking about the deductible options, it is
not there in ICC Lord. There will be
co-payment options in Elevate plan.
In NB 2.0, there will be deductible options ranging from ₹20,000 to ₹1 lakh. There are no
deductible options in Superstar.  There are
many options. You can reduce your premium by choosing a deductible option ranging from ₹ 20,000, 25,000, 50,000, ₹ 1 lakh to
₹ 1 lakh.
Now we will talk about an attractive
cover in this plan which is maternity cover.
This cover will not be available in NBP 2.2, but
you can take it with this add-on in the Elevate plan or Superstar plan. If you
take the maternity add-on in the Elevate plan, the
premium will increase significantly,
but the maximum limit on the base ash will
be ₹ 1 lakh. You can get it covered after 24 months, it can be
reduced to one year also.
You will also get cover for surrogacy and other side in it. The maximum limit will be ₹ 1 lakh. If we talk about
Star Health Superstar Maternity, then
this will also be a add-on.
Option A, Option B and Option C will be available in it.
Under Option A, you can
choose the maternity option of ₹ 500 and ₹ 1 lakh yourself.  You will decide
which one you want to take but
there will be a waiting period of 24 months. Option B: Under Option B,
you will only get maternity cover of Rs. 30,000
but you can
get this cover after one year. New born baby
cover will also be available here. If
your life insurance is between Rs. 5 lakh to Rs. 1 lakh, then
you can take cover of Rs. 1 lakh for newborn baby. If it is Rs.
50 lakh or unlimited, then
you can take cover of Rs. 1 lakh for newborn baby.
Under Option C, you
can claim assisted reproduction treatment.
Now I will talk about the premium of all the three health
insurance plans. It is
very important to know the premium because the
premium will decide which
plan we are going to opt for and which one
suits our budget. So, you will get ICC
Lombard Elevate plan cover of Rs. 1 lakh
with power booster for two adults to two kids in Delhi
NCR for Rs. 2491,
whereas you will get unlimited time cover for
Rs. 2.00 lakh.
At the age of 40, two adults will
get a cover of Rs 50 lakh for Rs 1. You will get a cover of Rs 50 lakh
for Rs 7900. Star Health's Superstar
plan worth Rs 1 lakh will be available for Rs
37283, in which I have
added power booster. If you take unlimited calls
in it, you will get it for Rs 633. The price
comparison also goes towards Ice Lord. It is
comparatively economical in comparison to both these
plans and fundamentally also it is
a strong company. Rest you
decide as per your need
which plan suits you.
You can ask any questions or queries related to these three plans. I will
meet you in the comment box
in my next video. Till then Jai
Hind Jai Bharat.